[Music]
Hi there, my name is Mike and here's how
Copilot can help you reduce the effort
of data entry in Business Central.
Copilot is your AI companion for work
and it can now suggest values for blank
fields in all of your cards and document
pages so that you don't have to look up
related records to see what values you
need to set. um you don't need to look
up that record you just created
elsewhere and you also don't need to go
and search the web for answers that you
need to input into those cards and
pages. Let's take a look how this works.
So for my first task in Business
Central, I'm going to create and
register a new customer. We'll pick a
local
customer and that's pre-filled a few
fields. For example, I set the country
region to US and it's pretty standard
for Business Central. So let's start by
entering the name Adventure Works. And
notice how I now have a new icon here
that sits neatly inside this input box.
And this is how I can ask Copilot to um
suggest values for this field, but also
for related fields inside this group of
fields inside inside this fast tab. So
as you can see, Copilot has done its
work and has come back and is now got
this very visually distinct way of
communicating to me where it's provided
suggestions within this fast tab. So
it's already corrected the name
Adventure Works by capitalizing it. And
I can actually check right here uh what
Copilot has done or why where the
suggestion comes from. So here it's
simply capitalized for proper
formatting. Fantastic. Let's keep that
suggestion. And um notice how uh it
actually saved that value only just now
as I chose to keep it. And this is a
really critical point for you to
understand uh when working with copilot
here. So um when Copilot provides
suggestions, those suggestions are not
automatically saved to Business Central,
Copilot gives me those suggestions. So I
can choose what to do with them. If I
choose to keep them, they get saved. I
can choose to modify them. I can choose
to discard them or just ignore them and
then they won't get saved. So that's a
really important point for you to
understand. Let's check out some of the
other suggestions that Copilot came up
with here. So we've got a credit limit
of 6,000. Where did that come from? I'll
use the info icon to find out. So, it
turns out that in my company, uh, we
typically set the credit limit to 6,000.
It's a frequent choice, as Copilot says
over here. I'll also keep this value.
That's probably what I was going to
input
myself. We have a salesperson
code. I'll choose to keep that one. And
we have a responsibility center as
well. And this is the most recently used
value. But um typically here copilot
will also you know intelligently select
different values from these lookups
where uh it will look at the values and
see what is the most appropriate that
matches this record contextually based
on the other fields on that record. So
here because this is a US customer uh it
would have picked also North America as
my responsibility center that's a
closest match with this being a US
customer.
So, Copilot uses these different mech
mechanisms of most recently used, most
frequently used values, but also uh
intelligent selection from a predefined
choice and option fields and in lookups
as well. But those kind of mechanisms
don't work so well when you have, you
know, public information such as address
and contact details for a customer. So,
here I've just put Copilot to work using
that same button to uh search the web.
It's now searching the web on my behalf
uh powered by Bing. And what it's doing
here is it's trying to find a matching
um customer website for Adventure Works
um and fill out these fields for me. So,
here we go. It's found um the Adventure
Works website. Yes, that actually looks
like the right one. It's gone and found
the address in uh Tennessee. It's also
found the phone number and email address
of that website. So, it's done all of
this for me without me having to go and
switch apps and do that browsing myself.
And if uh that looks roughly what um I'd
expect from the Adventure Works site, I
can now choose to actually keep all of
these values with one click. And notice
what happens as I do that. Copilot goes
through each field um it saves it now um
and runs the usual field validation
routines which will make sure that this
value matches all of my rule set, all of
my business rules in Business Central.
Now there's a very important point here
which is that um as you choose to keep a
value um it may trigger setting values
for other fields where copilot already
has a suggestion and in that case all of
the ALbased logic wins over copilot
suggestions shall we say in other words
um we will treat uh how business central
typically operates in terms of you know
setting field values automatically for
you as something that overrides any
suggestion provided by copilot.
All right. So, for my next task, I would
like to create and register a new fixed
asset. Now, this is not something I do
every day. So, I'm going to need all the
help I can
get. Let's create a new
asset. And I'm going to just register a
new printer that we've uh
purchased, an inkjet printer, LC 105.
And I've misspelled that, but that's
that's also just to illustrate a point
that Copilot helps with correcting uh
your language as well. So I'm going to
show you now the keyboarding experience
because uh this is a very integral part
of u field editing. Now um so if I use
the alt i shortcut, it's going to again
ask copilot to help me out fill out um
this field but also other fields within
this fast tab. And in just a few
seconds, it's come up with some
suggestions for me to go look at. So
first of all, it's corrected my typo
there. chose inkjet printer. Uh it's
filled out some other fields, but just
to show you that keyboard experience, I
can tab through all of these fields and
other controls just as I normally would.
Copilot does not get in my way, but I've
also got a simple way for me to choose
whether I want to keep this value and
move to the next. So, by hitting enter,
I can accept the value and move to the
next field. If you've used that power
user feature called quick entry, it's
pretty much the same concept. Enter will
accept the value, move to the next quick
entry field. So I'm just hitting enter,
enter, enter enter. But sometimes I
don't want that value. So here for the
location code, I'm not quite sure what
the consequences are of selecting prod.
So in this case, I'm going to use
backspace or delete uh or escape to
actually cancel um copilot suggestion
and just return to the previous value of
the
field. And if I do want to do a quick
change to a field, I can use the F2 key
to actually um simply modify the field.
And now I can switch that to a different
employee like Lena Townsend. All right,
let's try one last one here. So I've got
a couple more fields for depre
depreciation to set up. Um starting with
number of depreciation years. Now I'm
not quite sure what this is or what I
should set. So I'm going to ask Copilot
to help me out while I enter today's
date. And notice how I can interact
fully with Business Central as I
normally would to enter data, run any
actions, navigate around even while
Copilot is processing. it never gets in
your way. And let's come back with one
suggestion for five. Let's see what five
is. So five is okay. Inkjet printers
typically have a useful life of around
five years. So this is the last of our
mechanisms that we the co-pilot uses to
suggest a value. So when it can't find a
recently used value, a um a more
frequently used value or run a web
search or um or intelligently select
from some uh from some lookup. uh it
actually uses the power of AI and its
foundational training of the model to
actually come up with some kind of
suggestion here. So here it's come up
with five and just to illustrate what
happens as I choose to leave the page
here without keeping or discarding that
value. Uh business central will remind
me hey just so you know uh you still got
one suggestion that you haven't
reviewed. So this is a great place where
I can actually choose to keep or
discard. Um, and like I said, only if I
choose to keep explicitly will these be
saved in Business
Central. All right, that was a quick
tour of how autofill with Copilot works.
Uh, and this is going to help you
eliminate that tedious data entry uh in
all the records that you have to enter
into Business Central. All right, so if
you upgrade to update 26 of Business
Central, you get to try out this feature
yourselves. Um, and you can do that on
any environment and on any language as
well. Uh but do note that the ability to
search the web will be available later
during the wave. Uh finally, Copilot is
actually ready to work also with your
custom fields and your custom pages as
well. Um and if you're a developer
watching this, if you're a partner who
has some solutions, some extensions,
there's no um direct extensibility or
code you need to write uh to get your
fields to work with Copilot this way.
Um, but check out the link uh down below
this video where uh you can read all
about how to influence Copilot's output
and improve the output of Copilot and
its suggestions for your particular
fields. All right, this is when you stop
watching this video, you open up
Business Central, you get hands-on and
you try it out yourself. Um, hey, if you
enjoy this video, like and subscribe and
uh I wish you a productive day and
please give us some feedback uh about
how it goes with using Copilot to
autofill your fields. Thanks for
watching.